Preliminary Inventory to the John H. Moore Miscellaneous Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
John H. Moore Miscellaneous Papers,
1982-1985
84060
Hoover Institution Archives
14 manuscript boxes (5.8 linear feet)
Minutes, reports, studies, memoranda, and correspondence, relating to the activities of the National Science Foundation in furthering scientific research and education in the United States. Includes a report by J. H. Moore on the 11th Conference between Soviet and American Youth, Irkutsk, 1982, which he attended as an American delegate. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Moore, John H. (John Hampton), 1935-
Access
Collection is open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1984.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Conference between Soviet and American Youth (11th: 1982: Irkutsk); National Science Foundation (U.S.); Reagan, Ronald.; Education--United States.; Education.; Russia (Federation); Science--United States.; Soviet Union--Relations--United States.; Soviet Union.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Relations--Soviet Union.
- National Science Board file, circa 1982-1984
  - General correspondence (Box 1, Folder 13-000)
  - Outdated directories (Folder 13-000a)
  - Meeting agendas (Folder 13-002)
  - 236th-240th meetings, (1982 June 16-Nov. 19)
  - 241st-246th meetings, (1983 Jan. 19-Aug. 19) (Box 2)
  - 247th-252d meetings, (1983 Sept. 15-1984 May 11) (Box 3)
  - 253d-261st meetings, (1984 June 20-1985 May 17) (Box 4)
  - Minutes of Executive Committee meetings (Box 5, Folder 13-003a)
  - Executive Committee (Folder 13-004)
  - Committees (Folder 13-004a)
  - Budget Committee (Folder 13-006)
  - Planning and Policy Committee (Folder 13-007)
  - Programs Committee (Folder 13-008)
  - Minorities and Women Committee (Folder 13-009)
  - 15th Board Report Committee (Folder 13-010a)
  - 16th Board Report Committee (Folder 13-010b)
  - Ad hoc committees (Folder 13-011)
  - Commission on Pre-College Education in Mathematics, Science and Technology - General correspondence (Box 6, Folder 13-012)
  - Commission on Pre-College Education in Mathematics, Science and Technology - Reports, etc. (Folder 13-012a)
  - Information on members (Box 7, Folder 13-014)
  - Branscomb, Lewis M.
  - Cota-Robles, Eugene H.
  - DeVries, Ralph M.
  - Flawn, Peter
  - Fried, Ernestine
  - Good, Mary Lowe
  - Kasha, Michael
  - Knapp, Edward A.
  - Kruytbosch, Carlos
  - Langenberg, Donald N.
  - Massey, Walter E.
  - Miller, William F.
  - Neal, Homer
  - Nierenberg, William A.
  - Ragone, David V.
  - Salpeter, Edwin E.
  - Shakhashiri, Bassam Z.
  - Notes from the National Science Board (Folder 13-015)
  - Budget items, Miscellaneous (Folder 13-018)
  - Congressional Report (National Science Foundation) (Box 8, Folder 13-019)
  - Commercial competition policy (Folder 13-021)
  - National Science Foundation - university grant relationship (Folder 13-022)
  - Legislative chronology - FY, 1983 (Folder 13-023)
  - Cost of research adjustment (Folder 13-025)
  - National Science Foundation notices (Folder 13-026)
  - National Science Foundation guide to programs (Folder 13-027)
  - Science and technological innovation activities (Folder 13-029)
  - Vannevar Bush award (Folder 13-030)
  - Alan T. Waterman award (Folder 13-030a)
  - National Science Foundation minority graduate fellowship awards (Box 9, Folder 13-030b)
  - Grants and awards - FY, 1983 (Folder 13-030c)
  - Infrastructure Task Group
    - General (Folder 13-031)
    - Background information (Folder 13-031a)
    - Instrumentation (Folder 13-031B)
    - Indirect cost recovery (Folder 13-031d)
    - Research and development - Universities and Colleges (Folder 13-031f)
- Declassified U.S. government records, 1984
  - 2018 release of declassified records, 1984 (Reading room workstation)